Thank you so much Elon for joining me,
and also having us here at Tesla Global
Engineering Headquarters. It's so
amazing to see kind of new technology
innovations, all talented engineers here
as well.
>> Yes.
>> In this May, you were also on the
delegation to China as well. You have
met with President Xi. What's your
[music] impression about President Xi as
a leader?
>> Well, I it seems like a great leader. I
mean, he's
um
under his tenure, [music] China has
prospered immensely. I mean, I've seen
it firsthand. Like you you
if you visit China [music] and you see
it the the amount of progress that
happens from 1 year to the next or even
within a year. [music]
Um you can it's very visible. Like you
can see the the new buildings, the new
infrastructure, [music]
and um and it's also obvious to see that
uh I just walking around the streets,
[music] the increased prosperity of the
average Chinese citizen has increased
tremendously. And that's hap- well,
that's you know, [music] it's happened
under President Xi's, you know, while
he's been the leader of China. So so
he's clearly done a very, you know, done
an excellent job [music] and is very
capable.
>> Tesla Gigafactory Shanghai has always
done an incredible job. You praise your
teams many times.
>> Yes. [music]
>> So what kind of advantage or
breakthroughs do you think that uh
to making the Shanghai factory a very
important position in Tesla's global
blueprint? And what ultimate kind of
confidence [music] do you think this
will, you know, unfold uh especially in
the market?
>> Well,
I mean,
China just has a very strong inherent
ability [music] to do manufacturing
well. And this has been true not just in
present days, but [music] for the past
two or 3,000 years. I think that to be
totally frank, the magic of Tesla
Shanghai is
>> [music]
>> because of Chinese
to be totally
>> Because it's in China at least, right?
>> Yes.
We what we have is um
the Tesla
um China team [music] is just incredibly
talented
uh and hard working and trustworthy. Um
>> [music]
>> and uh they have
the the quality is excellent and the
efficiency is excellent.
So the Tesla Shanghai factory is a is a
gem. You know, it's it's and it's
beautiful it's beautiful actually if
anyone's ever [music] been there.
Um and we also care a lot about taking
care of the workers and making sure
they, you know,
uh they're good health care [music] and
good food and enjoy coming to work. It's
very important.
So,
>> Absolutely. I get I I I think we can
tell like all your uh stuffing Shanghai
factory they're very enjoying the
working there. [music]
So, um
we're talking about next hot topic
recently. We probably we can call
September is the Cybercat month. Have
you seen the videos like all the people
gather around that?
>> I guess it's
>> It's It's goes very very quickly.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's pretty cool cuz we
designed the car to look futuristic.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz I think um
you know, from a fashion standpoint, we
don't we don't want uh
as the the the aesthetics of the street
to stay stagnant. You You want to evolve
the
uh
what what do cars look like? And also, I
think maybe even clothing. Like we
should be
Like there was there was rapid fashion
evolution in the '50s, '60s, '70s, '80s,
'90s, and probably time to
uh make things look more futuristic.
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> And then how you see the kind of market
potential for Cybercat? You know, it's
it's
>> [music]
>> it's like, you know, it's really future
futuristic, but how long it can really
come to the reality or real life?
>> Well, we have the Cybercab um which has
as you know, has no steering wheel or
pedals or side mirrors or rearview
mirror um operating
uh commercially in Texas [music] right
now.
And it will soon be operating
commercially in uh Florida and Nevada
and a number of other states.
And probably by middle of next year,
it'll be operating commercially in in
California.
>> Absolutely. I think all the changes uh
is happening really fast. You know, it's
just like everyday we have to to look
social to see the kind of improving or
breakthroughs about AI or other old
uh tech topics. So,
>> Yeah, I mean, AI is just so crazy. It's
I mean AI the rate of AI software
improvements
uh so and and major announcements is so
rapid that it's it's makes my head spin.
You know, and I'm [music] in you know,
I'm in AI and it still makes my head
spin.
>> industry but you still have to
>> It's still [music] shocking.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know, sometimes I'll like when I
go to bed there'll be some big AI
breakthrough and then when I wake up
there's an AI breakthrough and by the
time it gets to lunch there's another AI
breakthrough.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's why even during this break you
have to check some others.
>> yeah, I probably have to check some
others.
>> Yeah.
So talking about like AI models, Tesla
had the latest what version, right? The
latest release about the Grok 4.7.
>> Yes.
>> I think this is your most focused these
two days. I I just saw you post on
social saying that you know, the Grok
bot is already in your Tesla. Tell us
like what's the reactions, what's the
latest
you have received from?
>> Yeah, I mean
Well, we just [music] we were we we
release a new model, you know, roughly
every month or two.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so
um
>> [music]
>> and it it's a cool Grok 4.7. It's a
solid workhorse [music] of a model. Um
it's not as it's not as good as say
um
Opus 5.5 that just got released. Uh but
uh
also we're um
we've only been around for about 3 years
doing AI whereas Anthropic's been around
for 6 years.
So
um
so I I would expect that we probably
uh catch up to Frontier sometime
>> [music]
>> next next year.
Most likely. In the meantime, I think
Grok is very useful for many things.
Um and Grok bot uh
that's kind of like a
personal digital assistant. Um has
>> [music]
>> uh been very popular.
Um and is growing
about 100% a month.
So it's growing very rapidly. [music]
>> I think you are very humble you saying
that like Grok 4.7 is not a perfect
wine, but we know that although uh have
experienced a little bit delay, but you
know that people are already very
fascinated or interested to know because
Grok 1.7 already being trained by uh
>> [music]
>> SpaceX real-world engineering data.
>> So, do you think
>> Only a little bit so far.
>> A little bit. Okay. So, do you think
that this will be one of your secret
weapon to kind of break through the AGI
ceiling cuz currently, you know, that
the models are have the challenge for
data.
>> Yes. Well, I think we've got
um a real opportunity [music] with the
SpaceX training data and maybe with the
Tesla training data to
um make AI extremely [music] capable in
real-world engineering.
So, what Anthropic did extremely well
was make AI
um excellent [music] at software
engineering.
Um but no one has yet made AI excellent
at real-world engineering.
And I think that's an opportunity for
Grok using the training data from SpaceX
and Tesla
uh to be excellent at real-world
engineering.
>> You mentioned many times like
previously, Chinese models also uh doing
a fascinating job. So, currently, what's
the most impression breakthroughs for
Chinese models in your understanding?
>> Well, they've they've been um
the Chinese
>> [music]
>> AI models are generally um outstanding,
actually. I mean, you can see on the
sort of
>> [music]
>> uh intelligence rankings the es-
especially given the limited amount of
compute [music] that the Chinese um
AI companies have, the
uh the performance is excellent. I'd
rate probably China as being by far the
best in terms of performance per unit of
compute. And uh as I've said uh publicly
um
you know, I think [music] China's going
to address the compute limitation in I
think faster than most people expect. Um
>> [music]
>> my rough guess would be that China
addresses the compute constraints with
lithography and chip making in about uh
two or three years.
>> [music]
>> Two or three years. We will really
expecting to this time. So, what are the
challenges facing for AGI in early
September in the G20 visual session, you
have raised a very serious concern about
the compute and electricity shortages.
You mentioned that probably China have
way more capability about electricity
infrastructure.
>> Yes.
>> And can you elaborate a little bit more
about this gap? And
you know, what areas do you think the
Chinese industry and capability can help
to get a new breakthrough for the
specifically on the electricity
>> infrastructure for the whole world. It
was just a statement of fact that China
think is a China like earlier this year,
China passed [music] the electricity
output of the United States, Europe, and
India combined.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. And and continuing [music] to
increase significantly.
Um
So, if
if China reaches um
>> [music]
>> the same GDP electricity output of the
US, which I think is likely, then China
would would go from where it is now
roughly three three times the US
electricity production to probably four
times, which would be proportionate to
the population difference.
>> Talking about the topic like AI safety,
what kind of crucial consensus do you
expect?
>> Yeah, I think um
maybe there could be a working committee
to figure [music] out safety. Um
because it's I think in order for safety
to work, it's it can't just [music] be
regulation in the US or regulation in
China. It's got to be we you know, how
do we how do we apply [music] apply
regulation fairly to AI produced in any
country,
>> [music]
>> but really China and and the US are the
the
the ones that really
matter here. Um
So, I think a really important [music]
thing that would be good for the safety
of AI for all of humanity.
>> Yeah. So, let's talk about the human
right robotics cuz I think this is also
a kind of industrial field US-China can
still also working together leading the
world.
And also I I can give you one example
for the Optimus. It's really amazing,
really impressive. So, before interview,
we have a
a kind of interactions. We play uh rock,
paper, scissors with Optimus.
>> Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah, we just won the first two rounds,
and Optimus won all the remaining.
That's really impressive.
>> Well, robots have a very fast reaction
time, so it's going to be
very difficult to beat a robot for
reaction time.
Um
cuz we we are somewhat constrained by
our biology. But, a robot, you can just
improve the actuators, improve the
sensors, improve the the frame rate of
the cameras, uh
increase the amount amount of AI
computer is, and it's going to just
fundamentally be much better, um
and have faster reactions than humans.
Um I enjoyed watching the
the robot games.
I mean, everyone in America was
fascinated by that, but
>> Yeah, you said it.
>> all over US social media.
>> Yeah, you said it's very entertaining to
watch, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, but other than that
>> Well, but it's it's entertaining to
watch, but it also shows you uh the
progress of humanoid robotics.
>> Exactly. Um like, it wouldn't be
entertaining to watch if the robots just
fell over.
>> Of course.
>> Uh so, but you know, the robots like
boxing, and then like
>> wrestling
>> wrestling, running, doing gymnastics. Uh
it's pretty cool.
>> Um
>> So,
I mean, the future's going to have a lot
of robots.
>> Yeah.
>> Like, a lot a lot.
>> Yeah. You mentioned that you're seeing
another 10 years, right? There will be
>> Yes.
>> the population for humanoid robots will
surpass 1 billion.
>> Yes.
>> So, that's that's
>> I think that's an easy prediction to
make.
>> Easy prediction, maybe within 10 years.
>> [music]
>> I'd say no later than 10 years, I'd say.
>> yeah.
So, what what Let's talk about what's
the real life will look like in 10
years, you know, when there are so big
you know, number of population of
humanoid robots, and also you mentioned
that one humanoid robots will have the
five times of production productivity
for human.
>> Pretty much.
>> Yeah. So, what what the life will be,
and then I mean, specifically like like
ordinary people, how we can cope with
the
the living, you know, with all AI kind
of dominated the world?
>> Well, I think my So, I I I let me focus
on the what's the 90% likely outcome,
which is the prosperous, the good
outcome.
>> Mhm.
>> We don't want to get complacent
regarding the 10% but may probably of a
bad outcome. So, we need to It's
important for us to pay close attention
to AI safety. But let me tell you about
the 90% positive outcome. The 90%
positive outcome is that everyone's got
robots that are their their buddies. Um
and
if you think of like Star Wars, we had
C-3PO and R2
>> D2.
>> Um and they were friendly, helpful
helpful robots. [music]
Um Well, wouldn't it be great if
everyone could have their own personal
C-3PO R2-D2?
>> Mhm.
>> But even better than that.
>> Yep.
>> Like more productive.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh that could uh take care of elderly
parents
uh or be a good guardian and watch over
the children or or be a teacher, like a
individualized tutor to your child.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
>> [music]
>> and uh and taking care of any jobs that
that that you can think of.
Um
So, that would be pretty cool.
>> Exactly.
>> everyone would like like to have a
future where that they can have their
own personal robots. And And then I
think you'll see many companies where
it's um
one person with uh
hundreds, maybe thousands of robots, but
like physical robots as well as digital
robots.
Um
so, the productivity of one person would
be greatly amplified.
Um and and my prediction is that is that
there will be
uh effectively universal high income.
>> Mhm.
>> Um in fact, uh it's not clear to me that
money will even matter in the future. Um
like if you if you scale the economy
the output of goods and services to a
level much greater than could possibly
be consumed by the number of humans on
the planet,
uh then you you have an age of abundance
uh that is that is difficult for us to
wrap our minds around because [music]
our entire evolutionary history has been
an evolution of uh constraints, [music]
of of um
where we didn't have enough food or we
didn't have enough uh
you know, heat or
and you know,
so that's certainly going to be true if
the output of goods and services is
constrained by the number of humans.
Because um
you know, humans take about 20 years to
grow up and then they are generally
retired for the last 20 years of their
life. So there's about 40 years, maybe
half the life of a human that's
productive. But then humans also need to
sleep and they need to
do the
eat and go to the rest restroom, you
know, all the basic stuff. Um
and um
and and so the actual number of hours
that that most humans can work is maybe
>> [music]
>> around 40 to 50 hours a week, something
like that. Um
whereas the robot will be happy to work
168 hours a week.
Continuous.
>> [music]
>> Um
and this and and the robot is instantly
at working age
and does not have retirement.
>> Exactly. Yeah. So you give us a very
beautiful picture about how the life or
how
highly efficiency about the productivity
by the humanoid robots. But for example,
you just mentioned that maybe money will
not be that kind of concern at that
time. If
Yeah, if money will not be a for example
like a tool for exchange, in that kind
of world, do you how do you think that
we can try to prevent uh you know, the
only a handful of few [music]
tech giants in you know, controlling the
all the resources and is specifically
how ordinary people do you think they
can claim their share in this kind of
full abundance?
Yeah, what I'm trying to say is that I
think that there will be a level of
abundance that [music] is more than
anyone could possibly consume.
Um I mean, I think it's going to get
pretty wild like
where if you want a if if you want a
castle, you know, um the robot will
build you a castle.
Um
so it's not it's not like
it's it's not as though like the robots
will be hoarded by a small small number
of It like actually the robots I think
will be
they will saturate on human demand,
meaning that [music] they will be they
will do more than anything humans could
possibly think of.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
and
>> [music]
>> and and and they'll run out of things to
do for humans.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
because there is a finite amount of
things you could do for humans [music]
within reason. Um
so
I think the robots will actually run out
of things to do for humans [music] and
then they will do things for themselves
because they they've run out of things
to do with for humans.
So
um and and probably probably there will
be
I mean
like my prediction is like
as you talked about
at least a billion humanoid robots
within 10 years. Yeah. Probably less
than 10 years.
Uh
>> [music]
>> I think that continues to grow uh and
probably
if if if if if if you assume that things
roughly double per year then then that's
about every three or four years you have
a [music] 10x increase.
>> Yes.
>> So
um you know, maybe that would mean say
in 15 years there are 10 billion robots.
>> 10 billion just 15 years.
>> years
100 billion.
>> Exactly. So this that's why we we always
call it like AI world is changing
improving exponentially. Continue about
the cooperation between US China or what
areas we can do together. The space
exploration uh cuz currently many
Chinese commercial space
companies they are strive to
you know, to explore more use after the
successful land recovery. Um what's kind
of areas or avenues do you think
possible avenue do you think between
communications or corporations can can
get between US and China?
>> Well, I mean in space I think the most
important thing to achieve cooperation
with is to make sure that when
satellites are launched from the US or
China that we we closely coordinate
where what orbits the satellites are
going to to avoid a potential collision.
I think that's the most important area
of cooperation.
Um
and then in in in general I I would say
that
the important thing for space launch,
the fundamental breakthrough that's
needed is full and rapid reusability.
Um which we're hoping to achieve with
the Starship uh design [music]
um
by catching the the ship hopefully
around the end of next month
>> [music]
>> um and then re-flying the ship either
later this year or early next year. Um
and that will be a very important
breakthrough
um and I'm sure others will solve that
that problem as well and I'm pretty sure
China will will at some point solve that
problem, too.
Um but it's it's [music] the full and
rapid reusability of a rocket is the
fundamental breakthrough needed to make
life multi-planetary.
>> Continue to talk about multi-planetary
species. You always you have been always
believe that human should become a
multi-planetary species. So, tell us
what's the current crucial step for your
Mars mission.
>> Well, like I said, the the most profound
and and fundamental
in- invention necessary for
making life multi-planetary is rapidly
and completely reusable rockets.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
Oth- otherwise the costs are impossible.
Um
you know, with with our Falcon 9 rocket
we uh we recover the booster stage and
the fairing [music] but not the upper
stage. And this is like throwing away a
medium-sized jet on every flight.
Um and you can imagine if in air flight
[music]
if you had to throw away the planes
uh after every flight, uh you're
you're way far too expensive
>> [music]
>> to and and
and air flight would not be a realistic
option. Well, that's been true in
>> [music]
>> in rockets for for a very long time.
So, I can't emphasize enough and I've
said this so many times over the years.
Um
uh full and immediate reusability of of
rockets like aircraft
>> [music]
>> um
is the is the fundamental breakthrough
that's needed to extend life beyond
Earth
>> [music]
>> um
to make life multi-planetary and to
create self-growing cities on the moon
and Mars.
>> Mhm.
>> And and if we're the as soon as we're
able to create a self-growing city on
the moon or Mars, the probable [music]
lifespan of consciousness is
dramatically greater.
Uh because now [music] we don't have
uh all our eggs in one basket. Um
so if something would have
something wrong would go wrong with say
the [music] moon or or Mars or Earth,
but we've got human civilizations on all
three of those places, then our chances
of surviving are much [music] greater.
>> Of course. So three different planets.
So that's why we all have to do our
part. Follow
>> And also it's just super cool.
>> Exactly. We have to follow all the tech
giants' steps, try to
make our own self, try to be the become
multi-planetary species.
>> Yes, exactly. So I mean I classify these
generally as like there's two lines of
main lines of argument. One is the
defensive line, uh which is that it that
having having consciousness on multiple
heavenly bodies uh greatly improves the
probable lifespan of civilization.
Um
>> [music]
>> that's the defensive argument. It's you
can think of it as life insurance for
life as a whole.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> [music]
>> the uh but the one I find personally
that drives me more is actually the the
inspiration argument.
Uh because you see that that like life
cannot just be about solving [music] one
sad problem after another.
There must also be things that make make
you excited to wake up in the morning.
>> Exactly.
>> That make you look forward to the
future.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
that make life worth living.
And the being a spacefaring civilization
is one of those things.
>> I totally agree with that. So So you
know you had you you once list like five
areas you care about most. Like uh
uh
uh sustainable energy, space, uh and
also the internet, AI, and gene editing.
Looking ahead for another 10 years, are
there any new frontiers you want to that
list?
>> Well, I I I
biological enhancement with like
Neuralink, uh this company I created
with some other people,
um
where where um
we we want to try to solve the bandwidth
constraint that humans have. Uh so,
um
so so cuz you can imagine like even in
the most benign scenario where the AI is
uh super friendly and wants to do
everything you can
it wants to make you happy, just
um
our rate of communication is too slow.
So, um
our like the average the
peak human bandwidth is only about 100
bits per second, roughly. Um
and uh
our input bandwidth is much higher
because of vision. So, there we maybe
have
it's a debatable point, but you know, a
a megabit per second or a few a few
megabits per second from our eyes, which
are effectively like cameras.
Um
But, our output bandwidth is really low,
maybe 100 bits per second, whereas
computers are communicating at trillion
bits per second.
So,
uh anything we can do to increase the
communication speed of humans will
improve the I think the alignment of
humans and machines.
Um cuz otherwise the the the
to an AI that is communicating at
[music] at a terabit a second,
um talking to a human will be like
talking to a tree.
>> Exactly.
>> you talk to a tree, it's it's takes a
long time to respond.
>> Let's talk about the challenge for young
people. You
>> [music]
>> mentioned that. You also talk about
education like in the AI world. And also
I had I watched that in your uh
headquarters here, you have a sign like
you can come back to school in Tesla as
well. Means which means that in every
age you can have the opportunity to come
back to to learn always to follow the
latest uh kind of bricks uh breakthrough
uh in uh AI world. But, what what about
kind of suggest suggestions or your
predictions? At that time, how for
example like a 20-year-old young people,
they can get [music] their fulfill their
self-worth rather than being left left
behind, you know, during [music] this
massive transition?
>> My recommendation for education [music]
would be to get as broad-based an
education as possible. And that includes
arts and sciences, engineering, uh
wide general knowledge. [music]
Like
in order to know what to ask the robots
for, you need to be able to formulate
the question.
And with the broadest [music] possible
general knowledge, you'll be better able
to formulate the questions or what they
call prompt engineering, I guess. Um
You got to convey your what your wishes
[music] to the robot.
And
as crazy as it sounds,
we will run [music] out
There will be so many robots and so much
AI that the AI will actually be eager to
hear any request that you could possibly
have.
>> Mhm.
>> Um because [music] that request will be
fulfilled immediately.
>> Yeah.
Your last visit to China is in May. If
you you got to have an opportunity to
bring one American entrepreneur for
visiting China for the very first time,
what will be the most experience you
want him to have first?
>> Well, I I generally recommend um
I I mean, as much time as as as that
person can devote to China, they should
go because China has got so many things
to see.
Um so I don't mean to I mean,
but like usually people don't have they
have they don't have infinite time, so
at a minimum,
uh they they should see obviously
Shanghai, Beijing. I recommend Xi'an,
the Terracotta Warriors. Uh I took the
bullet train from Beijing to Xi'an. That
was a great experience. Train stations
are amazing. Um
>> [music]
>> the Terracotta Warriors is one of the
wonders of the world.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
and um
And just And just make sure you look out
the window and And you're not on your
phone.
Cuz there's so much [music] to see.
>> Yeah, like you always recommend everyone
to experience to go and see China by
themselves.
>> Yes. Because any words I I any words I
say do not do justice [music] to the
incredible majesty that is China. It's
awesome.
>> Really appreciate for your words. Thank
you so much Elon for uh sitting down
with CCTV Business Channel and Elon we
truly hope to see you again very soon in
Beijing.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you Elon. Thank you so much.
>> Generally, I just like to say China is
awesome um and an incredible country and
I encourage people [music] from around
the world to visit China and experience
it for themselves.